

#### **PROFILE**

I am currently studying Software Engineering with Digital Technology (PwC) at Queens University Belfast.

I enjoy educating people on the impact of technology and how to use certain technologies as demonstrated within my role assisting in junior IT classes.

I am also an active member in the Queen's University Computing Society by attending talks hosted by the society and by participating within the 2020 Hack the COVID Hackathon. Within this event I, along with a team, presented our solution to a coronavirus specific problem to a panel of judges. I also participated in the 2021 Pediatrics Hackathon, in which I developed a mock app to assist in the flow of information from a responding paramedic to a specialist.

#### CONTACT

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/adamlogan42

Personal Website

https://adam-logan-portfolio.netlify.app/

⊕ GitHub

https://github.com/adamlogan17

**Email** 

adamlogan42@gmail.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### **Development Languages**

- Python
- Java
- HTML
- CSS
- **JavaScript**
- C++

#### **Applications**

- Microsoft Office
- G suite
- Azure
- Vantia

# ADAM OGAN

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

#### **EDUCATION**

## Software Engineering with Digital Technology Partnership **Queens University Belfast**

2020 - 2024Level 1

Level 2

Architecture and **Networks** 

83 Professional & Transfer Skills

86

Databases

Data Structures and 85 **Algorithms** 

82

Fundamentals of Maths for Computing

Software Engineering and 91 Systems Development

84

Software Design **Principles** 

88 Cyber Security

84

93

Web Technologies

Service Oriented Programming

Programming 88



## A-Levels School Belfast High School

2018 - 2020

Computer Science (A\*); Mathematics (A); Chemistry (A)

77



### **Belfast High School**

2016 - 2018

10 GCSEs A\*-A including English and Maths

## **PROJECTS**



#### **Web Technologies Project**

Within this project my team was tasked to create a web-based pointand-click escape room game. This demonstrates my creativity through creating a theme, story, and puzzles for this game. This project also shows my knowledge of web technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.



Relfast A-Level Project
School Upper Sixth (Year 14)

For my A-level project I created a hotel booking system in Python with a GUI. During this project I produced documents detailing the stages of development such as research & analysis, design, and testing. I used several well-known Python libraries such as matplotlib, tkinter and sglite3.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Interpersonal Skills

As can be seen above within my university projects and my work experience, I have been a part of many team projects which has assisted me in developing my communications skills and my ability to work effectively in a team.

#### **Time Management**

This skill is highlighted through my work experience as it demonstrates I can keep to deadlines given to me, by being organised. This skill is also proven by the fact that I managed to have a part-time job while attending school full-time.

#### Willingness to Learn

Within my spare time I read up on new concepts and technologies which I do not cover in university such as machine learning and the Linux command line. I also delve deeper into the technologies in which I study in university such as looking into the security issues of web technologies and exploring the NumPy and Pandas libraries in python.

#### **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

#### Running

This hobby of mine demonstrates that I am determined as I do not give up when tired, but I push on until the end of a task.

#### Reading

I enjoy reading as it allows me to broaden my horizons and expand my knowledge within the tech industry.

#### **Programming**

My interest in programming is one of the reasons why I decided to pursue a career in software development. The main aspect of programming which I enjoy is the many ways a problem can be solved.

#### **AWARDS AND QUALIFICATIONS**

- Civica Award (Achieved by obtaining the highest mark in my Level 2 Software Engineering and Systems Development Module)
- Microsoft Al Fundamentals
- Microsoft Security Fundamentals
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- put PwC Digital Acumen Badge
- Alteryx Designer Core
- Understanding Business, Language and Tourism (Level 2)
- Bronze Duke of Edinburgh Award

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## pwc

## PwC, Tech Consultant

21/09/2020 - Current

Throughout the three placements I gained a variety of experience in cloud, IoT, finance transformation, Salesforce and Google Apps Script. I have been on four projects as a project manager, test manager and developer. I also have had the chance to travel across the UK, to attend internal events, hackathons and training sessions.

During these placements I worked on projects large, small and even just myself proving that I can integrate within any sized team and that I can work autonomously. Not only do I have experience with working on projects, with varied sizes, but I also worked on projects that spanned three continents (CTech Poland, PwC India, PwC Middle East and PwC South Africa), demonstrating my ability to work within a multicultural team. Within my roles I have interacted directly with clients by sending status reports and by attending meetings.

I also managed to obtain certifications to demonstrate my knowledge in *Alteryx* and *Microsoft Azure*. In my more technical roles, I gained real world experience with technologies and disciplines such as web app development, *Python*, *Vantiq*, *REST APIs* and the *Azure SDK*. On top of this I completed training in *UiPath*, *PowerBi* and *Excel*.



#### Eason, Sales Assistant

19/02/2020 - 24/08/2020

My job at Eason's was heavily communication based. Everyday my role as a sales assistant required me to be polite and present myself in a friendly yet professional manner to the customers and my co-workers. This allowed me to develop my confident demeanour. Alongside this, working on the tills required cash handling which granted me the opportunity to prove I am trustworthy and thorough in all tasks I am asked to undertake.



#### **PSNI**, Software Engineer

29/07/2019 - 23/08/2019

At my 4 weeks' work experience with the PSNI, where I was placed within ICS in which I worked on several projects which were developing a facial recognition software, researching different handwriting recognition software and assisting ICS in finding a cloud storage provider. These projects tested both my problem-solving skills and my logical thinking skills.



#### Catalyst, Product Designer

17/06/2019 - 20/06/2019

When I was at the Generation Innovation work experience program, I was placed within a team, and then my team was assigned to LibertyIT. My team and I then had to pitch our solution to a problem given to us by LibertyIT, to several members of the company. After this we had to deliver the same pitch to the other teams on the program. This work experience program helped me to become a more confident speaker.